（水月）ヘヘヘヘ…。
（水月）なんでか
かなり見張りが手薄になってる。
It seems like there are
a lot fewer guards around.
今なら逃げきれるかも。
We could make a run for it now.
Let's look for Sasuke.
（重吾）サスケを捜そう。
You go on ahead.
I'm going to look for my blade.
先に行っててよ。
僕は　自分の刀を探してからだ。
鍵はすぐ見つかった。
けど　刀がどこにもなくってさ。
I found the key right away,
but my blade is
nowhere to be found.
こいつらに刀を
取り上げられたんだろ？　なら→
They confiscated it, right?
Then look in their armory.
まずは　武器庫を見ればいい。
行くぞ。
Let's go.
What? You're going to help me?
へぇ～　手伝ってくれんだ。
You're all right, Jugo.
Unlike that Karin.
（水月）やっぱ　いいやつだな。
重吾って。　香燐と違ってさ。
って　香燐は
どこ行ったんだろ？
Speaking of which,
where'd she go?
Want to look for her?
捜すか？
ん～。
いないと意外と
静かすぎる気もするね。
Without her around,
it's a little too quiet…
どうしよう。
What should we do?
（カカシ）敵の連携の
手の内がわかってきた。
I'm beginning to understand
how the enemy is coordinating this.
今度は　こっちからだ！
Now it's my turn!
（カブト）ククク…　相手のペースを
作らせるほど→
I'm not so naïve…
as to allow the enemy to act.
僕は　甘くないよ。
（ガリ／パクラ）口寄せの術！
– Summoning Jutsu!
♪～
まさか　ここまで…。
No way. Don't tell me…
That's…
こ　これは！
The past members of the Seven
Ninja Swordsmen of the Mist!
霧隠れ忍刀七人衆の
前任者たちだ！
Among the legendary
Seven Ninja Swordsmen…
歴代の忍刀七人衆のなかでは
どの方も強い忍ばかりだ！
they've chosen the strongest ones!
選んでやがる！
（カカシ）忍刀七人衆か…。
The Seven Ninja Swordsmen…
エンスイ小隊まだか！
Nothing on the Ensui Platoon?
（エンスイ）あと少しです。
They'll be here shortly.
Maki of the Hidden Sand,
what about you?
（カカシ）砂隠れのマキ
そっちはどうだ？
We're ready to roll!
（マキ）あぁ　こっちはいけるよ！
All right, buy some time
for Ensui's platoon.
よし　エンスイ小隊の時間を稼ぐ。
みんな　一斉攻撃だ！
Everyone, attack together!
どうやら
ここにもないみたいだね。
It's not here either.
なくなってた霧の忍刀を
集めるって言ってたな。
You said you're gathering all
the lost Hidden Mist Blades.
なぜ　そこまでこだわる？
なんだよ。
Why are you so obsessed?
What?
You said you'd help me.
Don't tell me you're giving up?
手伝うって言ったくせに
もう　めんどくさいのかよ？
You're the one who gives up.
いや　ふだん
めんどくさがるのは　お前だ。
Except when it comes
to the ninja blades.
なのに　忍刀に関しては
必死になる。
チッ　こればっかりは
やる気を出さないとね。
I need one thing to keep me going.
忍刀七人衆の復活と
そのリーダーになることが→
Resurrecting
the Seven Ninja Swordsmen
and becoming their leader
is my dream.
僕の夢だから。
Resurrect?
復活？
あぁ。
Yeah.
Right now, the Seven Ninja
Swordsmen consists
今や　霧隠れ忍刀七人衆は
長十郎ってガキ一人。
of a single brat named Chojuro.
忍刀は代々
受け継ぐ習わしだけど→
Traditionally, the ninja blade is
passed down from
generation to generation.
Right now, there is only one blade,
known as the Hiramekarei.
今は　ヒラメカレイって刀が
一丁だけで→
Nothing else.
他は全部なくなってる。
The great blade, Samehada,
is in Kisame's possession,
大刀　鮫肌は鬼鮫が持ってるとして
抜け忍だし→
but he's a rogue ninja.
I finally got a hold of
the Executioner's Blade,
首斬り包丁は
やっと手に入れたのに→
only to lose it.
なくなっちゃったし…。
今は　正式には
ほぼ存在しない部隊だよ。
So officially,
that unit doesn't exist today.
今はね…。
For now, anyway…
The First and Last Opponent
駄目だ　やはり
いくら攻撃しても無意味だ。
The First and Last Opponent
It's no use.
No matter how many times we attack,
it has no effect.
どうすんだよ　あんなやつら相手に
しかも　忍刀七人衆だぞ！
What do we do against
guys like that?
They're the Seven Ninja Swordsmen!
長引けば
こちらが　どんどん不利になる。
The longer we keep this up,
the greater our disadvantage.
そんなに心配するな
あの術は　魂を封印するか→
Don't worry so much!
The Reanimation Jutsu
can be stopped
体を動けなくするかの
どちらかで止められる。
by sealing away the soul
or immobilizing their body.
それに再不斬以外
刀を持っていない。
And other than Zabuza,
no one is wielding a sword.
そうなりゃ　やつらの力も半分だ。
That cuts their strength in half.
No.
《いや…。
刀はちゃんと
持ってきたようだな》
It seems they brought their swords.
《全員分は無しか》
Not all of them have one.
（ガイ）更に霧が濃くなっていくぞ
これでは何も見えん。
The mist is getting even thicker…
We can't see through this.
サイレントキリングで音もない
耳でも駄目だぞ。
And there's no sound
with Silent Killing.
We can't even hear them.
まず　この霧を何とかしないと
連隊は不利だ。
We must do something
about this mist,
or the Allied Forces are
at a disadvantage.
（ガイ）何か策があるのか？
（カカシ）今　それを準備してる。
You have a plan?
I'm preparing it now.
ならば　それはお前に任せる。
Then I'll leave you to handle it!
リー　灼遁を追え　俺は爆遁をやる。
（リー）わかりました。
Lee! Go after the Scorch Style!
I'll take the Explosion Style!
Understood!
カカシ隊長　影真似影縛り整いました。
（カカシ）よし　俺につなげ。
Captain Kakashi!
I'm ready with my Shadow Possession
and Shadow Paralysis!
All right, fasten it to me.
エンスイは影真似の術の力を緩くし→
Ensui, reduce the strength
of the Shadow Possession,
まずは俺の動きに委ねてくれ。
はっ。
and stay focused on my movements.
Right!
山中サンタは心転身の術で
俺と入れ替われ。
Santa Yamanaka,
use the Mind Transfer Jutsu
to trade places with me.
お前の感知能力なら
この霧の中でも→
With your sensory skills,
you will be able to track and
find Zabuza in this mist!
再不斬を捜せるはずだ。
（サンタ）はっ！
Right!
再不斬を感知したら
影真似をつけた俺を→
Once you perceive Zabuza,
since I'll be under Shadow Possession,
再不斬を目視できるところまで
導いてくれ。
guide me to a location
where I can see him.
なるべく　うしろを取るようにだ。
Get me behind him
as close as you can.
やつを目視できたら
すぐに心転身の術を解き→
When I have
a clear sight of him,
immediately release
the Mind Transfer Jutsu
体を俺に戻してくれ。
and return me to my body.
再不斬と戦い　やつの影を踏みつけ
影を合わせる。
I will grapple with Zabuza
and step on his shadow
and get him into position.
そしたら　すぐにエンスイは影真似と
影縫いの２つの術の力を上げ→
At that point, Ensui,
immediately increase the power
of your Shadow Possession
and Shadow Stitching Jutsu
and bind him!
おもいっきり　やつを縛れ！
その後　マキが布縛りの術で→
Then Maki, completely immobilize Zabuza
with your Cloth Paralysis Jutsu!
再不斬の体を
動かぬように縛りあげろ。
はい！
やるぞ。
Yes!
Let's do this!
Right!
《心転身の術！》
Mind Transfer Jutsu!
俺たちでカカシさんをガードするぞ！
おう！
We're going to guard
Captain Kakashi!
Right!
でさ　他にも
いろいろ刀があってさ。
Anyway, there are lots
of other blades.
歴代の忍刀の中には
鬼鮫や再不斬　長十郎以外にも→
Among the Ninja Swordsmen
throughout history,
there were super masters besides
Kisame, Zabuza and Chojuro.
すごい使い手がいたんだ　まずは→
First…
雷を帯びた切れ味　最高の一本。
there's the wielder of
the Lightning Blade, the Fang,
a blade swathed with lightning
with the ultimate cutting edge…
雷刀　牙の使い手　林檎雨由利！
Ameyuri Ringo.
どんなガードをも叩き潰す。
The wielder of…
the Blunt Blade, Kabutowari,
that smashes through any defense…
鈍刀　兜割の使い手　通草野餌人。
Jinin Akebino.
すべてを突き刺し　縫い合わせる。
The blade that stabs
and pierces everything
and sews them together…
長刀　縫い針の使い手　栗霰串丸。
the Long Blade, the Sewing Needle.
Its wielder is
Kushimaru Kuriarare.
太刀筋に爆発の力を加えた→
The blade that adds explosive power
to one's swordsmanship…
爆刀　飛沫の使い手　無梨甚八。
the Explosive Blade: the Splatter.
And its wielder,
Jinpachi Munashi.
それから　干柿鬼鮫と同等に
大刀　鮫肌を扱った１人→
And the one who,
like Kisame Hoshigaki,
wielded the Great Blade, Samehada…
Fuguki Suikazan.
西瓜山河豚鬼。
そして　それらすべての
七刀を使いこなす→
And the one who could handle
all seven blades.
鬼人の再来と言われた
僕の兄　鬼灯満月。
The one known as the second coming
of the demon, my older brother…
Mangetsu Hozuki.
何より　この僕が→
And I am going to be the captain
of the new generation
新世代忍刀七人衆の隊長であり
そして！
of the Seven Ninja Swordsmen, and…
もう　いい。
大声で　しゃべりすぎだ。
Enough. You're talking too loud.
なんだよ
せっかくの締めだったのに。
Hey, I was coming to the climax.
お前の持っていた刀は
折れてしまったんだろ？
The sword you broke
in two, right?
あんなものより　新しく作れば
いいんじゃないのか？
Shouldn't you just make
a new sword?
なんにも知らないくせして…。
You don't know a thing.
あの刀には　ある能力がある。
That blade has a certain power.
（水月）断刀　首斬り包丁は
刃こぼれしない刀。
The Severing Sword,
the Executioner's Blade,
cannot be chipped or nicked.
いや…　刃こぼれが
直るといったほうが　いいかな。
No, a better way to put it is,
the blade repairs itself.
It cuts into humans,
then absorbs their blood.
人を斬り裂き
人の血を吸い続けることでね。
あれは　血中の鉄分で再生する。
It regenerates itself with
the iron present in blood.
《よし　見つけた！　心転身　解！》
All right! Found him!
Mind Transfer Jutsu, release!
《お願いします　カカシさん！》
Good luck, Captain Kakashi!
《よし　先手を取った！
All right!
He hasn't noticed me.
いける！》
I can do this!
♪～
フッフ　見事だ　白。
Splendid, Haku.
《再不斬をかばって
飛び込んでくるとは…。
I didn't expect him to jump in
to save Zabuza.
The boy… is already dead.
この子…　もう　死んでる…》
《多勢を相手にするには→
Zabuza's Hidden Mist style is
necessary in order to battle many.
再不斬の　霧隠れの術が要。
再不斬を狙ってくるのは
わかっていた。
So I knew that Zabuza would
be their target.
それを守るためには
他は　ただの盾にすればいい。
To protect him,
the rest can be mere shields.
再不斬をまるで命がけで守る白。
And Haku will protect Zabuza
with his life.
クックックッ…
今は　ただの人形だけどね。
Even though he is simply
a puppet now.
戦争では
なかなか　おもしろい演出に→
It must be quite a performance
out there on the battlefield.
なってるだろうな…》
《この子ごと　俺を斬るつもりか》
He intends to slash me along
with the boy?!
カカシ隊長！
Captain Kakashi!
♪～
ぐわぁ～っ！
チクショウ！
Damn it…
音も聞こえず
こうも　見えづらいんじゃ…。
If we can't hear them or
even see them…
カカシ隊長は　まだか！？
Isn't Captain Kakashi here yet?!
敵一人は　影をくっつけた。
I put a shadow on one enemy!
２人目は
影の接触時間が短すぎる！
There hasn't been enough contact
time with the second shadow!
これでは　動きを止められない！
I can't stop his movements!
接触時間って→
Contact time?
Don't tell me Zabuza cut down
Captain Kakashi?!
まさか　再不斬に
カカシ隊長が斬られたっていうのか！？
((ナルト：カカシ先生
また　Ａランク任務やるってばよ！
Give me another A-rank mission?!
ダメダメ！　再不斬と　白…。
No way!
Zabuza and Haku…
あれほどの強い忍相手に→
I can't believe everyone
came out unscathed
皆　無事だったのが
信じられないくらいだよ。
against such strong ninja.
ん～。
Huh…
まっ　もっと術を覚えて
修業して強くなってからだよ→
Well, learn more jutsu and train
to become stronger.
Then you can tackle
A-rank missions.
Ａランクなんてのは。
ん～　術もそうだけど→
You're right about learning
more jutsu.
守りたいもん
もっと　いっぱい見つけねえとな。
But I've also got to find other
things that I want to protect.
あの　白の兄ちゃんが言ってた。
Haku said to me…
人ってのは　大切な何かを
守りたいと思ったときに→
when a person has something
precious they want to protect,
本当に強くなれるってよ。
they can truly become strong
そっか
じゃ　お前もそう思うのか？
I see…
So do you feel the same way?
うん！　白の兄ちゃんと
再不斬見てたら　そう思った！
Yeah!
After watching Haku and Zabuza,
I started to believe that.
あのさぁ　あのさぁ！
Hey, hey…
カカシ先生ってばよ
じゃあ　これってどう思う？
Kakashi Sensei,
what do you think about this?
(何が？))
About what?
お前たちが
ナルトの最初の敵でよかった。
I'm glad you were
Naruto's first adversaries.
マキ　指示するまで　俺の後ろで→
Maki, stay behind me and
stand by with
your Cloth Paralysis Jutsu!
布縛りの術の準備をしておけ！
はい！
Right!
((ハァ…　ハァ…　ハァ…　どうしてだ？
Why?
なぜ　ついていけない？
Why can't I keep up?
くそ～！
Damn it!
うりゃあ～っ！
今のお前では　俺には勝てないよ。
You can't possibly defeat me
the way you are now.
なんだと？
What was that?!
(お前は　気づいていない))
You still don't realize…
再不斬…　お前は　あのとき→
Zabuza…
That time,
you hesitated killing Haku
白を斬ることをためらった。
そして　お前の内心は→
and you couldn't hide the unrest
in your heart over Haku's death.
白の死による
動揺を隠しきれなかった。
だが　今は違う。
感情のない道具ってやつだ。
But it's different this time.
You're just a tool
with no feelings.
もう　こんな戦いは
終わりにしよう！
Let's put an end
to a fight like this!
((あのさぁ　あのさぁ！
Hey, hey… Kakashi Sensei.
カカシ先生ってばよ
じゃあ　これって　どう思う？
What do you think about this?
何が？
うん…。
About what?
あいつら　敵だったけど…。
Well, those two were enemies…
なんかさ　なんかさ…。
I…liked those guys.
俺…　あいつら好きだった！
(これって　おかしいかなぁ？))
Is that weird?
《いや　俺もだよ》
No.
I feel the same way.
エンスイ　縛れ！
Ensui! Bind him!
《合図だ！　よし！》
That's my signal! Okay!
影縛りの術！
Shadow Paralysis Jutsu!
《お前らの死に様と涙は…》
The way you died and your tears…
《お互いの絆　そのものだったよ》
demonstrated your bond
to each other.
俺にも　忍として
守るべきもんがいろいろある。
I have many things I want
to protect as a shinobi.
再不斬と白…。
Zabuza and Haku…
こいつらの死に様も
そのひとつだ。
Protecting the way they died
is one of those things.
Especially since I am
their final enemy.
こいつらの最後の敵は
俺だったんだからな…。
《ナルト…　お前は　どう思う？》
Naruto… What do you think?
マキ　やれ！
はい！
Now, Maki!
Right!
くそ！
Damn it!
こ　これは…。
霧が　晴れていく…。
This is…
The mist is clearing…
よし！　これで　敵を目視できる！
All right!
Now we can see the enemy!
（マキ）この札があるかぎり
口寄せはできません。
If these tags remain,
they cannot be summoned.
この２体は
私が監視しておきます！
I will keep an eye on
these two bodies.
わかった…　穢土転生…。
All right…
The Reanimation Jutsu…
This is an unforgivable jutsu!
この術は　許せない…。
Sai, next we'll use your
Sealing Jutsu from the Foundation!
サイ　次はお前の
根の封印術を使う！
俺に続け！
（サイ）でも　あの術は僕には　まだ…。
You're up!
But…But I still haven't mastered
that jutsu…
ダンゾウが　お前を買っていたのは
たしかだろう？
Isn't it a fact that you were
highly regarded by Danzo?
もう　感情を抑える必要はない！
There's no need to suppress
your emotions anymore!
まっ…　俺も熱くなるまで
時間のかかるほうだが…。
Well… It takes me a while
to get upset too…
今回は　久しぶりに
沸点が低かった。
But this time,
my boiling point was low.
千の術をコピーした　コピー忍者のカカシ…。
Copy Ninja Kakashi has copied
a thousand jutsu…
これより　通り名どおり…。
And I'm going to use them
to their fullest extent!
暴れる！
（黄ツチ）かかれ～！
Attack!
（キバ）うらぁ～！
（赤丸）ワンワン！
Fang Over Fang!
牙通牙！
（シノ）秘術　蟲玉！
Hidden Jutsu! Beetle Sphere!
（ヒナタ）八卦空掌！
Eight Trigrams Air Palm!
（ネジ）八卦掌回天！
Eight Trigrams Palm Rotation!
ネジ兄さん！
Neji!
数が多すぎる…。
There are too many of them…
《こいつら
チャクラを吸い取るのか…》
So they absorb chakra…
柔拳法　一撃身！
Gentle Fist Technique…
Body Blow!
One after another…
There's no end to them!
次から次へと　キリがねえぜ！
Stop whining and move!
泣き言はいい　動け！
１体１体が強く　しつこい。
Each one is strong and persistent!
これでは　消耗戦になる。
This is attrition warfare.
黄ツチ隊長！　本部から連絡！
Captain Kitsuchi!
数千体が　我々の足もとを
通り抜けたそうです！
（黒ツチ）親父！
うるさい！　わかっとる！
（我愛羅）来たな…。
[スピーカ]皆様　お変わりございませんか？
美空ひばりです。
では最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
（宮本）『木曜８時のコンサート　名曲！
にっぽんの歌』　２時間スペシャル。
（松丸）今回は　ご覧の豪華歌手
１８組の皆さんによる→